（子供のアクマ）
あんな単純な回転に
引っ掛かんなよ
Don't be fooled by simple spin like that.
Moron.
ボケ
Hey, Demon.
（子供のペコ）
うぉーい アクマやい
Don't hit Smile.
スマイル たたくなよ
But, Peco... this guy sucks.
でもよ ペコ
こいつってば 全然ダメなの
Well, if it isn't Peco!
（アクマ）
おーよ！ ペコじゃねえか
（ペコ）誰だよ てめえ
Who the hell are you?!
（小泉(こいずみ)）ちっ！
（アクマ）何だって月本(つきもと)は—
Why'd he make such a lame return?
あんな浮ついた球 返すんだ
Match goes to Kong!
（主審）マッチ トゥ コン選手
Everyone involved in a game like that suffers!
あの手の試合は—
関わる人間
みんな苦しむことになるんだよ
Don't ever do that again!
二度とするな
Please don't hit me when my glasses are on.
（スマイル）メガネの上から
たたかないでくださいよ
Everyone knows better than that.
非常識だ
You're being too hard on Tsukimoto, Coach.
（大田(おおた)）
月本 責めるのは酷っすよ 先生
He won two whole games against Kong!
（山田(やまだ)）
コンから２ゲームも取ったんすよ
大して勝つ気もないやつが
冷やかしで打つんじゃないよ
This isn't a sport for guys dicking
around without caring if they win!
やめるか？ 卓球
You want to quit table tennis?
Yes.
（スマイル）やめます
そうしろ
Quit, then.
（小泉）ふん！
（山田）おい 月本
Tsukimoto!
（大田）待てって
Wait!
Leave him.
（小泉）ほっとけ
（ペコ）要するに甘ちゃんなんだよ
You're just a softy.
勝って なんぼだぜ
Winning's all that matters.
Hey!
（大田）おーい！
ハァ…
（オババ）昔とダブるかい？
50年以上前の自分と
Is he giving you flashbacks to yourself over fifty years ago?
Oh, Tamura.
（小泉）おお 田村(たむら)
He's not the type you can slap into submission.
ビンタ張って
言いなりになるような子じゃないよ
I know that.
知ってるさ
He practically never smiles.
（オババ）
めったに笑わない子だからね
スマイルって呼ばれてるよ
That's why they call him Smile.
A new age has dawned, and still I can't make a decision
My path is too straight for my taste, but I'll walk it
I can't choose just yet
I have to think about it
I have no idea what I want to do
I'm going crazy!
Comparing yourself to others just makes you depressed
You're alone in this world
You're always alone here
Still you're gonna do it, right?
Maybe there's nothing that only I can do
But there's no way that I
But there's no way that I won't try to leave my mark
I just want to have my fun, whatever the times
Win the next game and you go to the Interhigh, Wenge.
For all intents and purposes, your match with Kazama is the finals.
You can't beat him with those
sloppy serves you've been making today.
He had total control of the game.
Stop, Wenge. Don't go there.
I think he lost on purpose.
You're wrong.
（スタッフ）６番コート 準々決勝
On Court Six, we'll now begin
the quarterfinal match between
Hoshino of Katase High School and Sakuma of Kaiou Academy.
片瀬(かたせ)高校 星野(ほしの)選手
海王(かいおう)学園高校 佐久間(さくま)選手
It's been a while since I last played you.
お前と打つの 久しぶりだな
It's been four years and three months.
４年と３か月だ
俺の24勝92敗
My record against you is 24 - 92.
Whoa, both sides?
（ペコ）おっ 裏かよ
（アクマ）
今どき片面表でやってんの
お前ぐらいなもんよ
You're the only one who plays
single-sided pips-out these days.
Hoho, reverse penhold backhand and long pips?
（ペコ）ほえ～ 裏面？
しかも ツブ高(だか)
Times are changing.
時代さ
You're trying too hard.
無理しちゃって
You don't know how long I've dreamed of the day I'd play you again.
（アクマ）俺が お前と打つ日を
どれだけ夢見てきたか
What an admirable story.
けなげな話だな おい
Yes, it is.
（アクマ）そうさ
お前には分からないだろうよ
Not that you'd understand.
You were always #1.
いつだって お前が一番だった
You were great at everything you did and always the center of attention.
やることなすこと
あか抜けてて—
いつも みんなの中心だった
お前が右を向けば
みんな右を向く
When you looked to the right, everyone looked to the right.
When you laughed, everyone laughed.
お前が笑えば みんな笑った
You'd joke around, but you'd always get the job done.
おちゃらけてても
決めるところは決め—
You crushed even older players with ease.
年上だって簡単に吹っ飛ばす
Do you have any idea how I viewed you?
そんな お前を
俺が どういう目で見ていたか
俺が何を感じてたか
How I felt?
Yeah!
っしゃー！
Terrible.
下手くそ
Yeah!
っしゃー！
どうした アクマ
ずいぶん おとなしいじゃんすか
What's wrong, "Demon"?
You've gotten awfully quiet.
Let's have a top-spin contest, dude!
シャモケンやろうぜ
昔みてえによ
For old times' sake.
あい！
えい
Yeah!
っしゃー！
えい
クッソ！
Damn it!
Take this!
この！
えい
いや！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
えい！
アウト！
ゲーム トゥ 佐久間選手
Out! Game goes to Sakuma!
Shit... That's just petty, only using lobs and blocks.
チクショウ
ロビングやブロックばっかの
セコい卓球しやがって
フッ 卓球は進化してんだよ
Table tennis is evolving.
Your game might as well be a fossil in a museum.
お前の化石のような卓球は
博物館並みさ
Let's pick up the pace, Sweet Tooth!
巻いてくぜ お菓子バカ
What?
（ペコ）え？
（アクマ）もたもたしてっと—
Gotta wrap this up, or I'll be late for Kazama's match.
風間(かざま)さんの試合
始まっちゃうからよ！
I know you mocked me and called me "Professor Table Tennis."
（アクマの声）
お前が“卓球博士”って 俺のこと
バカにしてたのを知ってるぜ
しかし その努力が
実を結ぶこともあんだよ
But you know what? Sometimes effort pays off.
Your rubber and rackets always seemed to shine in my eyes.
お前のラバーやラケットは
いつも輝いて見えた
I had to watch you show off all those medals you went around winning.
あちこち出かけて
ぶんどったメダルを—
たくさん見せられた
俺が それを
どんな目で見ていたか
You don't know what it was like for me, seeing them.
But as time goes by, talent and environment stop being the only things that matter.
だが 時がたてば
才能や環境だけじゃねえ
Eventually hard work has its say!
努力だって発言権ぐらい
持ってくるんだぜ
お前は風間さんの
足元にも及ばねえ
You're nowhere near as good as Kazama.
（アクマ）っしゃー！
Yes!
っしゃー！
You've been lazily compromising on your game for years.
（アクマの声）
怠慢と妥協にまみれた卓球を
続けたお前に 何ができる
What can you do?
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
What can you do?!
（アクマの声）何ができるよ？
（主審）
マッチポイント　佐久間選手
Match point, Sakuma!
ヘッヘッヘッヘ
Damn you, Demon...
アクマ てめえ
（アクマ）ていっ
（主審）マッチ トゥ 佐久間選手
Match goes to Sakuma!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Peco, let me give you some advice.
ペコ お前に１つ
いいこと教えてやんよ
The only way to be sure you won't lose is to not fight.
絶対 負けない
唯一の方法はだな—
闘わないことだ
ヒヒヒ…
惰性で打つなら足洗えよ ペコ
Quit the sport now if you're just gonna coast along, Peco!
Otherwise you're just an eyesore!
うろちょろされんと
目障りだかんな
ク… クソ！
Damn it!
The only way to be sure you
won't lose is to not fight
（オババ）昔は よくも
死に物狂いで戦ってたね
It's hard to believe I used to
play like my life depended on it.
Wearing a "victory" headband and everything.
必勝の鉢巻きしてさ
You were lovely.
田村は可憐(かれん)だったからね
And terrifyingly strong at the same time.
それでいて恐ろしく強かった
Winning was everything back then.
勝つことが すべての時代さね
Losers would have their very character rejected.
負けた選手は人格まで否定される
勝てば官軍 負ければ賊軍
"The winners write history, and the losers are history."
I've seen that mentality wreck a lot of people.
そういう精神が生み出した
挫折を—
ずいぶん見てきた
今も変わらないけどね
Not that it's any different now.
（オババ）
あの子は変わった子だよ
He's a strange kid.
He has immense talent, but no interest in winning.
大きな才能を持ちながらも—
勝つことに まったく興味がない
えてして そういうもんさ
That's how these things go.
Talented people who know exactly who they are don't crave anything.
自分が何者か分かっている
才能のある者は—
最初から何も望まない
Those who don't know themselves
自分が何者か
分からない者ほど—
are always the ones who struggle hardest
to win, because they want to prove a point.
もがいて勝って
何かを証明したいんだよ
I want to take him there, is all.
僕は ただ
彼を連れていってあげたいだけだ
Once he gets there, something will change inside him.
行けば彼の中で何かが変わる
You think so?
（オババ）そうかね
Being hard on Tsukimoto won't turn back the clock for you.
月本 しごいたところで—
お前の青春は戻ってこないよ
Well done.
（卓(たく)）お疲れ
Thank you, sir!
Where's Kazama?
風間先輩は どこでありますか？
He's in the can again.
（卓）
あいつは また便所だ
Is he constipated?
（アクマ）
先輩は便秘でありますか？
（卓）ハハハ… いや 違う
No, nothing like that.
He always holes up somewhere before a match.
やつは試合が近づくと
必ず こもる
Kaiou
It's finally time for a boss fight.
いよいよボスキャラ登場だ
I hear he's on a 68-game winning streak!
68連勝中だと
He's a monster.
化け物だよなあ 実際
（生徒）
海王って４回戦以下で負けたら
即 退部だとよ
They say Kaiou kicks you off the team if you lose before the fourth round.
（生徒）ひえー マジかよ それ
Yikes... Seriously?!
（生徒）きょうび 卓球に
命懸けちゃってる連中なわけよ
They stake their lives on table
tennis, and in this day and age!
That's scary, man.
（生徒）ああ 怖(こえ)え
（生徒）見てみろよ 風間の顔
Look at Kazama's face. Just look!
ほれ
He's got the eyes of someone who's killed a man!
ありゃ絶対 人 殺してるな
そういう目だって
Shh! He'll hear you, idiot!
シーッ 聞こえるだろ バカ
高校生の顔じゃねえよ
That ain't the face of a high school student!
He's gotta be over thirty!
ぜってえ 三十路(みそじ) 超えてるって
On Court Eight, we'll now begin the quarterfinal match between Kong of Tsujidou High School
（主審）８番コート 準々決勝
辻堂(つじどう)学院高校 コン選手
and Kazama of Kaiou Academy!
海王学園高校 風間選手
（観客）風間ぁ！
Go Kazama!
Win it!
（観客）勝てよー！
（観客）抱いてくれー！
Be my lover!
Crush him, Kazama!
（観客）吹っ飛ばせ 風間！
Ah, so he's the hero of this little island country.
Look at his muscles.
He's got power, but I doubt he's light on his feet.
Make a good serve and go for a third ball attack.
Take an early lead and keep it.
Easier said than done.
Believe in yourself. You're better than he is.
Kazama!
（観客）風間ぁ！
（観客）こっち向いてくれ！
You can do it!
Heh, lively crowd.
First game: Kong to serve!
（主審）ファーストゲーム
コン選手 トゥ サーブ
ラブオール
Love all!
Yes!
So fast!
He's good...
（中国語の
チャイナの声）
I can't believe how fast his reaction time is.
A monster, huh?
化け物… か
（中国語の
チャイナの声）
He must have an opening somewhere...
Where is it?!
He's reading me. He's predicting my moves!
Show me your weakness.
I can't afford to let it end here!
Not here!
（ドラゴン）ぬおー！
My drive... With my drive!
（中国語の
チャイナの声）
（コーチ）ハア… うん
Match goes to Kazama!
（主審）マッチ トゥ 風間選手
Semifinal A
Kaiou
Sanada
Sakuma
Kaiou
Sanada
Semifinal B
Kaiou
Uesugi
Kazama
Kaiou
Finals
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Kazama
Kaiou
Sanada
Winner
Kazama
Kaiou
Interhigh Participants
Kazama Ryuuichi
Kaiou
Sanada Yoshiyuki
Uesugi Kenji
Kaiou
Sakuma Manabu
Your girlfriend?
No, my mother. She made me carry it.
She's the stereotypical country parent...
How long have you been living away from her?
Since I was eight.
That's when I joined the provincial team.
From then on, she brought me things once a week...
She worked in a candy factory, and she'd bring piles of their candy.
Did you have any favorites?
Well...
Her homemade wontons were good.
I used to always dream about losing my key...
It'll be a relief not to have any more dreams where I'm
the only one without a ticket.
Wenge...
Your life has just begun. You've only just reached the starting line.
I'm done for.
I don't mean table tennis. I'm talking about life.
And this isn't your coach talking.
This is the opinion of a friend who knows you well.
Heh.
Your words give me hope.
（ドラゴン）月本君
Tsukimoto.
ちょっと いいかね？
Do you have a minute?
Are you going back to school?
（スマイル）学校 戻るんですか？
（ドラゴン）ああ また練習だ
Yes. Back for more practice.
That's hard-core.
（スマイル）すごいや
They're all dimwitted and useless.
（ドラゴン）
使えないグズばかりで
話にならない
And they don't realize it, which makes it even worse.
自覚がない分 タチが悪い
You understand, don't you?
分かるだろう？
What?
I'll make a comfortable place for you at Kaiou.
私が海王に
君が生きやすい場所を作る
知ってのとおり海王は—
As you know, Kaiou was founded by a former table tennis pro,
創立者が元卓球選手でもあって
卓球への思いが強い
and it's passionate about the sport.
We have a dedicated practice hall that's available 24/7,
専用の練習場は24時間 使え—
and coaches from all over the world helping us every day.
朝晩は常時 海外からのコーチも
サポートしてくれる
練習は すべて
ハイビジョンで撮影され—
All our practices are filmed in HD and analyzed.
分析される
We have machines that can fire almost any type of shot,
ほぼ すべての球種を繰り出せる
卓球マシン
and ball collection machines.
集球マシン
道具は無料で提供され—
Equipment is provided free of charge.
すべてが最高水準でありながら
使い放題だ
They're all top quality products,
and you can use them all you want.
我々はラバーの手入れなどしない
We don't do rubber care.
Every three to four days,
ラバーは３日から４日
それも 山のようなラバーから—
you can select a few of the best
rubbers from a mountain of choices.
２～３枚
出来のいい物だけを選べばよい
無論 自分に合った道具の開発にも
相談に乗ってくれる
And of course, the school will also help you develop custom-made equipment.
For strength training, we've got a gym.
筋トレ　ジム
トレーナーは 最新の
スポーツ科学を学びながら—
Our trainers follow the latest sports science to understand our bodies
and keep them in top shape.
我々の体を理解 整備し—
Nutritionists manage our meals.
栄養士は我々の食事を管理する
With their eyes fixed on our distant futures at all times,
常に我々の遠い未来までも
見据えながら—
they even give us the chance to go on overseas tours.
海外遠征もサポートする
We have a comprehensive library of all the major foreign tournaments.
海外の大きな試合もすべてそろった
充実したライブラリーがあり—
If you ask, someone will go record any
match you want, anywhere in the world.
頼めば世界中どこの試合でも
撮ってきてくれる
You can't get to nationals or onto the world stage all by yourself.
君１人では
全国大会 世界へも行けないだろう
だが 君には才能がある
But you have talent.
Katase isn't worthy of you.
片瀬は ふさわしくない
海王へ来るべき人だ
You belong at Kaiou.
いずれ迎えに行く
I'll come to pick you up one day.
Count on it.
必ず
インターハイ 頑張ってください
Do your best at the Interhigh.
遅(おせ)えな 風間
Kazama's late.
He takes forever in the can.
あいつ ホント 便所長(なげ)えよな
All your play was sloppy!
とにかく雑だ！
すべてのプレーが！
格下の相手に抜いて打てるほど
偉いのか？ お前ら！
You jerks think you're so good you can pull your punches against weaker players?!
Don't get cocky! Or else you won't
stand a chance against the very best!
おごるなよ！
上じゃ通用しねえぞ！
（部員たち）押忍！
Yes, sir!
Everyone meet in the gym when we get back!
（卓）帰ったら全員
体育館に集合！
Got it? Answer me!
いいな？ 返事！
Yes, sir!
（部員たち）押忍！
（卓）以上！
Dismissed!
Yurie.
（卓）百合枝(ゆりえ) 今 来たのか？
Did you just get here?
Okay, you go back in Yurie's car, Ryuuichi.
じゃあ 竜一(りゅういち)は百合枝の車で帰れ
Yes, sir.
（ドラゴン）押忍
Is that the coach's daughter?
（部員）
監督の娘さん？ かわいい
She's cute.
ＣＭに出とる子じゃけえのう
Yeah, she's in TV commercials.
（部員）いいな 風間
Kazama, you lucky dog.
I hear he's living with her at the chairman's house.
（部員）理事長宅に
あん子と一緒に住んどるんじゃと
They're living together, huh?
（部員）憎らしか
リア充め
How dare he have a life.
Ryuuichi and Yurie are cousins. Their relationship is pure.
（卓）
竜一と百合枝は いとこ同士で
清い交際だ
Liar.
（部員）ウソじゃ
（部員）信じられんぜよ
I don't believe it.
（部員）父じゃけえよ
Fathers are blind.
You'll pay for that later! Get on the bus!
（卓）お前ら あとでしごくぞ！
バスに乗れ！
（部員たち）押忍！
Yes, sir!
Attention, ladies and gentlemen.
（アナウンス）
場内においでの皆様に
お知らせいたします
All games scheduled for the day have ended.
本日 予定されていた競技は
すべて終了いたしました
We ask that you vacate the arena in a timely manner.
速やかに 場内からのご退場を
お願いいたします
（アナウンス）
勝手ながら 閉門時間は
６時とさせていただきます
The arena will close at 6:00.
We regret any inconvenience.
A red sun stares at me
The world goes blurry when I yawn
My wishes fluctuate like a metronome
Everything tells me this is the end
I do have some dreams, you know
Sometimes we breathe
and just seem to inhale the smoke of someone
somewhere out of sight
Then all our great energy just seems to melt away
I don't understand this wonderland
I won't get wet even if it rains
This is a wonderland
Once I've made it through this long tunnel
I'm sure that someone will kiss me